http://www.markelcorp.com/privacy-policy

About Markel
Markel is a holding company for insurance, reinsurance, and investment operations around the world. Get information on our structure, operations, leadership, history, financials, and more.
Learn more
Press releases
Markel Style
Newsroom
Suppliers
Markel at a glance
Industry ratings
Insurance
Back
Insurance
Markel can seem like a complex organization, but our main operation is insurance.
Learn more
Classic cars and boats
Energy and environmental
Personal lines
Workers comp
Risk Solution Services
Careers
Back
Careers
Take charge of your career. Search jobs, and read more about working at Markel.
Learn more
Career areas
Job search
Our culture
Rewards and benefits
The selection process
Markel internships
Markel underwriter training program
Investor relations
Back
Investor relations
For our current and potential investors, find stock information, SEC filings, quarterly and annual reports, and more.
Learn more
Annual reports
Quarterly reports
SEC filings
SEC 16 filings
Letters to shareholders
Press releases
Locations
Back
Locations
Markel has 73 offices in 21 countries. View our interactive map to find and get directions to our office locations.
Learn more
Markel locations list
Claims
Back
Claims
Find out how to file a claim with our insurance and reinsurance operations.
Learn more
File a claim
Vendor services
Contact us
Back
Contact us
Contact us
Learn more
Markel
4521 Highwoods Parkway
Glen Allen, VA  23060+1-800-446-6671 (toll free)
Send us an email
Specialty
Back
Specialty
Markel Specialty includes all of Markel’s insurance operations in the US and international teams in Bermuda, Dublin, and London. We underwrite a wide range of risks for large corporations, small businesses, not-for-profits, and individuals.
Learn more
International
Back
International
Markel International writes insurance and facultative reinsurance business across the UK, Europe, Canada, Latin America, and Asia Pacific.
Learn more
Global Reinsurance
Back
Global Reinsurance
Markel Global Reinsurance writes reinsurance treaties on a quota share and excess of loss basis.
Learn more
Casualty treaty
Casualty facultative
Property treaty
Public entity
Specialty treaty
Nephila
Back
Nephila
Nephila is a leading investment manager specializing in reinsurance, weather risk transfer, and ESG-driven business. Nephila offers a broad range of investment products focusing on instruments such as insurance-linked securities, catastrophe bonds, insurance swaps, and weather derivatives.
Learn more
State National
Back
State National
State National Companies is a leading provider of niche property and casualty insurance and services operating in two distinct business segments.
The Program Services division bridges distribution and capacity in specialty insurance segments. The Lender Services division provides an array of portfolio protection solutions and industry leading technology to enable lenders to manage their risk.
Learn more
Markel Ventures
Back
Markel Ventures
Markel Ventures owns and operates a family of companies outside the insurance industry.
Learn more
Our approach
Our companies
Acquisitions
Markel Corp
About Markel
About Markel
Markel is a holding company for insurance, reinsurance, and investment operations around the world. Get information on our structure, operations, leadership, history, financials, and more.
Learn more
Press releases
Markel Style
Newsroom
Suppliers
Markel at a glance
Industry ratings
Insurance
Insurance
Markel can seem like a complex organization, but our main operation is insurance.
Learn more
Classic cars and boats
Energy and environmental
Personal lines
Workers comp
Risk Solution Services
Careers
Careers
Take charge of your career. Search jobs, and read more about working at Markel.
Learn more
Career areas
Job search
Our culture
Rewards and benefits
The selection process
Markel internships
Markel underwriter training program
Investor relations
Investor relations
For our current and potential investors, find stock information, SEC filings, quarterly and annual reports, and more.
Learn more
Annual reports
Quarterly reports
SEC filings
SEC 16 filings
Letters to shareholders
Press releases
Locations
Locations
Markel has 73 offices in 21 countries. View our interactive map to find and get directions to our office locations.
Learn more
Markel locations list
Claims
Claims
Find out how to file a claim with our insurance and reinsurance operations.
Learn more
File a claim
Vendor services
Contact us
Contact us
Contact us
Learn more
Markel
4521 Highwoods Parkway
Glen Allen, VA  23060
+1-800-446-6671 (toll free)
Send us an email
Search
Specialty
Specialty
Markel Specialty includes all of Markel’s insurance operations in the US and international teams in Bermuda, Dublin, and London. We underwrite a wide range of risks for large corporations, small businesses, not-for-profits, and individuals.
Learn more
International
International
Markel International writes insurance and facultative reinsurance business across the UK, Europe, Canada, Latin America, and Asia Pacific.
Learn more
Global Reinsurance
Global Reinsurance
Markel Global Reinsurance writes reinsurance treaties on a quota share and excess of loss basis.
Learn more
Casualty treaty
Casualty facultative
Property treaty
Public entity
Specialty treaty
Nephila
Nephila
Nephila is a leading investment manager specializing in reinsurance, weather risk transfer, and ESG-driven business. Nephila offers a broad range of investment products focusing on instruments such as insurance-linked securities, catastrophe bonds, insurance swaps, and weather derivatives.
Learn more
State National
State National
State National Companies is a leading provider of niche property and casualty insurance and services operating in two distinct business segments.
The Program Services division bridges distribution and capacity in specialty insurance segments. The Lender Services division provides an array of portfolio protection solutions and industry leading technology to enable lenders to manage their risk.
Learn more
Markel Ventures
Markel Ventures
Markel Ventures owns and operates a family of companies outside the insurance industry.
Learn more
Our approach
Our companies
Acquisitions
Home
Legal disclaimer and privacy policy
Legal notices
Last updated: January 2020
Conditions for website use
By
using this web site, you signify your agreement to the terms and conditions
contained in these legal notices. If you do not accept these terms and
conditions, please do not use this web site. Please read these terms carefully.
We reserve the right to add, delete or otherwise modify portions of these terms
at any time. You should visit this page periodically to review the terms and conditions.
User access to and use of this web site is subject to all applicable federal,
state and local laws and regulations. Virginia law and Federal law will govern
the interpretation and enforcement of these terms and conditions.
Disclaimer
This
web site has been prepared solely for the purpose of providing information
about Markel Corporation and the services and products it offers through its
subsidiaries. Markel has compiled this web site in good faith. However, no
representation is made as to the completeness or accuracy of the information it
contains. In particular, you should be aware that this information may be
incomplete, may contain errors or may have become out of date. The reports
filed by Markel with the Securities and Exchange Commission and listed on this
web site speak only as of the respective dates on which they are filed or used
by Markel. Markel makes no commitment, and disclaims any duty, to update any of
those reports. MARKEL DOES NOT WARRANT THAT THE WEB SITE WILL OPERATE ERROR-FREE
OR THAT THE WEB SITE AND ITS SERVERS ARE FREE OF COMPUTER VIRUSES OR OTHER
HARMFUL MATERIAL. IF YOUR USE OF THE WEB SITE OR THE SITE’S MATERIAL RESULTS IN
ANY COSTS OR EXPENSES, INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, THE NEED FOR SERVICING OR
REPLACING EQUIPEMENT OR DATA, MARKEL SHALL NOT BE RESPONSIBLE FOR THOSE COSTS
OR EXPENSES. THIS WEBSITE AND THE INFORMATION CONTAINED HEREIN (INCLUDING ANY
REFERENCES TO PRODUCTS OR SERVICES) ARE PROVIDED "AS IS" WITHOUT ANY
WARRANTY OR IMPLIED TERM OF ANY KIND. MARKEL, TO THE FULLEST EXTENT PERMITTED
BY LAW, DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES, INCLUDING THE WARRANTY OF MERCHANTABILITY,
NON-INFRINGEMENT OF THIRD PARTY RIGHTS, AND THE WARRANTY OF FITNESS FOR A
PARTICULAR PURPOSE. ALTHOUGH MARKEL STRIVES TO PROVIDE THOROUGH AND ACCURATE MATERIALS
ON ITS WEB SITE, WE MAKE NO WARRANTIES ABOUT THE ACCURACY, RELIABILITY,
COMPLETENESS, OR TIMELINESS OF THE MATERIAL, SERVICES, SOFTWARE, TEXT,
GRAPHICS, AND LINKS. IN NO EVENT SHALL MARKEL OR ANY OF ITS SUBSIDIARIES BE
SUBJECT TO LIABILITY FOR ANY DAMAGES OF ANY KIND, WHETHER DIRECT, INDIRECT,
SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, CONSEQUENTIAL OR OTHERWISE, WHETHER OR NOT ADVISED OF THE
POSSIBILITY THEREOF, UNDER ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, ARISING OUT OF OR IN
CONNECTION WITH THE PROVISION OF INFORMATION ON THIS WEB SITE OR SITES LINKED
TO THIS WEB SITE.
Insurance coverages are underwritten by member companies of Markel Corporation, including Markel American Insurance Company; Glen Allen, VA.  Not all products and services may be available in all jurisdictions, and the coverage provided by any insurer is subject to the actual terms and conditions of the policies issued. Certain products and services are provided through various non-admitted insurance company subsidiaries of Markel Corporation and are offered through licensed surplus lines brokers. Non-admitted insurance carriers do not generally participate in state guaranty funds and insureds are therefore not protected by such funds.
Forward looking statements
This is a Safe Harbor statement under the Private Securities Litigation Reform
Act of 1995. This web site and the site’s material, including documents and
presentations within it, contain forward-looking statements that involve risks
and uncertainties. Forward-looking statements may be identified by the use of
terms such as believes, expects, estimates, may, intends, plans, will, should
or anticipates or by the negative thereof or similar expressions, or by
discussions of strategy. Markel Corporation has based the forward-looking
statements on beliefs, assumptions, expectations and projections about future
events using information available at the time such statements were made. These
forward-looking statements are subject to risks, uncertainties and assumptions
about Markel. Discussion of factors that could cause actual results to differ
materially from management's projections, forecasts, estimates and expectations
is contained in Markel's SEC filings, including Forms 8-K, 10-Q and 10-K.
Markel cautions the reader not to place undue reliance on its forward-looking
statements because the assumptions, beliefs, expectations and projections about
future events may and often do materially differ from actual results. Markel
undertakes no obligation to update any forward-looking statement to reflect
developments occurring after such statement is made.
Copyright notice
Material
contained on this web site is copyrighted material by Markel Corporation. All
rights reserved. No materials from this web site may be copied, reproduced,
republished, posted, or distributed in any way, except as expressly permitted
herein or with the prior consent of Markel Corporation.
Trademark notice
MARKEL and its Design are registered trademarks of Markel Corporation. All
other trademarks are property of Markel Corporation or its subsidiaries unless
otherwise designated. The use of these marks, except as expressly permitted
herein or with the prior consent of Markel Corporation is prohibited.
Reference to analysts
Although Markel Corporation may reference or provide a list of analysts on this
web site as a convenience to you, any opinions, estimates or forecasts
regarding Markel Corporation's performance made by these analysts are theirs
alone and do not necessarily represent opinions, forecasts or predictions of
Markel Corporation or its management. Markel Corporation does not by its
reference above or distribution imply its endorsement or sponsorship of, or
concurrence with, such information, conclusions or recommendations of the
analysts or firms.
Links to other materials
Some
of the links available to you through this web site will allow you to leave the
Markel web site. The Internet sites and the material that you can access there
are not under the control of Markel, and Markel makes no representations and
disclaims all liability with respect thereto. The links are provided only for
your convenience, and their inclusion does not constitute nor imply approval or
endorsement by Markel of the sites or their content. If you decide to visit any
third-party sites using the links from this web site, you do so at your own
risk.
Indemnity
By
using this web site, you agree to defend, indemnify, and hold harmless Markel
Corporation and its subsidiaries, their officers, their directors, their
employees and their agents, from and against any and all losses, claims,
damages, costs and expenses (including reasonable legal and accounting fees)
that Markel may become obligated to pay arising or resulting from your use of
the web site or your breach of these terms and conditions. Markel reserves the
right to assume or participate, at your expense, in the investigation,
settlement and defense of any such action or claim.
Violations of terms and conditions
In
the event that you violate or attempt to violate any of the terms and
conditions contained in these legal notices, Markel reserves the right to
terminate your access to this web site immediately, at our sole discretion,
with our without notice of any kind. We also reserve the right to involve and
cooperate with the law enforcement agencies, and to pursue a civil lawsuit or
criminal prosecution for any and all alleged or actual illegal activities
involving this web site.
Legal disputes, severability and choice of law
If there is a legal dispute of any kind about or arising out of the use if this web site, the laws of the Commonwealth of Virginia will govern such dispute without regard to conflict of law rules. You agree that if any part of these terms and conditions is found to be unenforceable, the remainder of these terms and conditions will remain in full force and effect. By using this web site you expressly agree and submit to personal jurisdiction and exclusive venue in the state and federal courts located in Henrico County, Commonwealth of Virginia.
Privacy Policy
Markel and its US subsidiaries and affiliates (each, “Markel”,
“we” or “us”) is committed to safeguarding your privacy. This Privacy Policy
sets out Markel’s personal information collection and sharing practices in
relation to the personal information that we collect and use for the
administration of insurance policies, reinsurance contracts and the provision
of services.
This Privacy Policy describes how we handle personal information that we
collect from various sources, including:
·
information we receive from you on applications, customer
feedback and survey responses, or other forms, telephone recordings with our
representatives, and call centers
·
information about your transactions with us, our affiliates, or
others
·
information we receive from you when you use our website, social
media pages, or apps
·
information we receive from other third parties, such as agents,
producers, consumer reporting agencies, service providers, inspection agencies,
or publicly available information from social media services, or governmental
agencies
·
information we receive for recruitment purposes, this includes
information that you or your recruitment agency supply in relation to your
candidacy (e.g. your CV, application form) pre-offer, and background checks
(administered by a third party) post-offer
Depending on your
relationship with us, you may receive other privacy notices from us providing
additional detail about our privacy practices.
Information we may collect about
you
The types of personal information we collect and share depends
on the product or service you have with us.  This information can include the
following:
·       your
name, mailing and email address(es), telephone number, date of birth, gender,
marital or family status, identification numbers issued by government bodies or
agencies (i.e.,  Social Security or FEIN, driver’s license or other license
number) employment, education, occupation
·       your
policy coverage, claims, premiums and payment history from your dealings with
us, our affiliates, or others
·       your
financial history from other insurance companies, financial organizations or
consumer reporting agencies, including but not limited to payment card numbers,
bank account or other financial account number and account details, credit
history and credit scores, assets and income and other financial information
·       your
medical history and records
·       your browsing
history, search history, information on your interaction with our website, your
application, or advertisement
·       other
personal information required in order for us to provide products and services that
you have requested
Personal information does not include:
information for certain legitimate or lawful purposes in some or all of the
following ways:
·       to
correspond with clients, beneficiaries and claimants in order to facilitate the
performance of a contract with you or to take steps to enter into a contract
·       to comply
with a legal obligation
·       to
comply with law enforcement, court and regulatory bodies’ requirements
·       to
identify and prevent fraud
·       to
modify, personalize or otherwise improve our services or communications
·       to
gather market intelligence, communicate with and tailor offers to individuals
performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of
an official authority
How we may use your personal
information
We may use your personal
information in the following ways:
·       to
process your transaction with us, for instance, to determine eligibility for
coverage, to process claims or to prevent fraud
·       to
identify you and to carry out any identity checks as may be required by
applicable law and best practice at any given time
·       to
recover any payments due to us and where necessary to enforce such recovery
through the engagement of debt collection agencies or taking other legal action
·       to
analyze it in order to understand the service we provide and in order to
improve our business
·       to
manage our infrastructure, business operations and comply with internal
monitor calls and transactions to ensure service quality, compliance with
procedures
·       to
carry out background and reference checks, in relation to recruitment
specifically
·       to provide
you with information about the online services or required notices
Sharing your personal information
We
use and share your personal information with affiliated and non-affiliated
third parties for the purposes of underwriting insurance, administering your
policy or claim and other purposes as permitted by law.
We
may disclose personal information about you to the following types of third
parties:
·       service providers,
such as insurance agents and/ or brokers, claims adjusters, or reinsurers
·       governmental
authorities and non-affiliated third parties as permitted by law
We
restrict access to personal information about our customers/claimants to those
individuals who need to know that information to provide products and services
to our customers/claimants or as permitted by law.  We train our employees
to safeguard personal information.  We maintain reasonable physical,
electronic, and procedural safeguards to guard your personal information in
accordance with applicable data protection laws.
Do
Not Track signals:  We do not support this at this time.  This practice maybe
revised in the future.
Social
Security numbers
We
protect the confidentiality of your Social Security number by reasonable
physical, electronic and procedural safeguards as required by law.
Children’s
privacy
We
do not knowingly collect personal information from minors, including children
under the age of 13.  Our products, services, and website are not intended for
use by minors.
Links
to other websites
This
website may contain links to other third-party websites. If you follow a link
to any of those third- party websites, please note that they have their own
privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for
their policies or processing of your personal information.
International
visitors
We
have operations outside of the United States.  For the reasons outlined in this
Privacy Policy, we may disclose personal information to affiliates and third
parties in other countries.  Laws governing the privacy of personal information
vary in different countries and my not be the same as those where you reside.
For residents of AZ, CT, GA, IL, ME, MA, MN, MT, NV, NJ, NC, OH,
OR, and VA
Under
state law, under certain circumstances, you have the right to access and
request correction, amendment or deletion of your personal information that we
have collected from or about you.  To do so, contact your agent, or contact us
at privacy@markel.com, or call (888) 560-4671, or write to Markel Corporation
Privacy Office, 4521 Highwoods Parkway, Glen Allen, VA 23060.
Changes
to our Privacy Policy
We
reserve the right to amend this Privacy Policy at our discretion and at any
time. When we make changes to this Privacy Policy, we will post the updated policy
on the Website and update the policy effective date. Your continued use of our
Website following the posting of changes constitutes your acceptance of such
changes.
For a
copy of our Privacy Notices, please click here:  U. S. Consumer Privacy Notice
For
further information, please contact us at privacy@markel.com, or call (888) 560-4671, or write
to Markel Corporation Privacy Office, 4521 Highwoods Parkway, Glen Allen, VA
23060.
For residents of California
This Privacy
Policy for California Residents supplements the information contained above and
applies solely to all visitors, users, and others who reside in the State of
California (”consumers” or “you”). We adopt this notice to comply with the
California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 (“CCPA”) and any terms defined in the
CCPA have the same meaning when used in this notice.
The
categories or personal information we have collected from consumers within the
last twelve (12) months includes the following:
Identifiers
Your
name, mailing and email address(es), telephone number, date of birth, gender,
marital or family status, identification numbers issued by government bodies
or agencies (i.e.,  Social Security number or FEIN, driver’s license or other
license number), or other similar identifiers.
Personal
Information categories listed in the California Customer Records Statute
(Cal. Civ. Code 1798.809(e)
A
name, signature, Social Security number, physical characteristics or
description, address, telephone number, driver’s license or state
identification card number, insurance policy number, education, employment,
employment history, bank account number, credit card number, debit card
number, or any other financial information, medical information, or health
insurance information.  Some personal information included in this category
may overlap with other categories.
Protected
classification characteristics under California or federal law
Age
(40 years or older), race, color, ancestry, national origin, citizenship,
religion or creed, marital status, medical condition, physical or mental
disability, sex (including gender, gender identity, gender expression,
pregnancy or childbirth and related medical conditions), sexual orientation,
veteran or military status, genetic information (including familial genetic
information).
Commercial
Information
Your
policy coverage, claims, premiums and payment history from your dealings with
us, our affiliates, or others.  Your financial history form other insurance
companies, financial organizations or consumer reporting agencies.
Biometric
information
Your
medical history and records.
Internet
or other similar network activity
Browsing
history, search history, information on a consumer’s interaction with a
website, application, or advertisement.
Geolocation
data
Physical
location or movements.
Sensory
Data
Audio,
electronic, visual, or similar information.
Professional
or employment-related information
Current
or past job history or performance evaluations.  For recruitment purposes,
this includes information you or your recruitment agency supply in relation
to your candidacy (e.g. your CV, application form) pre-offer, and background
checks (administered by a third party) post-offer.
Non-public
education information (per the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (20
U.S.C. Section 1232g, 34 C.F.R. Part 99))
Education
records directly related to a student maintained by an educational
institution or party acting on its behalf, such as grades, transcripts, class
lists, student schedules, student identification codes, student financial
information, or student disciplinary records.
Other
personal information required in order for us to provide products and
services you have requested.
Information
excluded from the CCPA’s scope, includes but not limited to:
·       health or medical
information covered by the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act
of 1996 and the California Confidentiality of Medical Information Act or
clinical trial data
·       personal
information covered by certain sector-specific privacy laws, including the Fair
Credit Reporting Act , the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act or California Financial
Information Privacy Act (FIPA), and the Driver’s Privacy Protection Act of 1994
Sales
of Personal Information
In the preceding
twelve (12) months, we have not sold your personal information.
Your
Rights and Choices
The
CCPA provides consumers (California residents) with specific rights regarding
their personal information. This section describes your CCPA rights and
explains how to exercise those rights.
Access to Specific
Information and Data Portability Rights
You have the right
to request that we disclose certain information to you about our collection and
use of your personal information over the past 12 months.
Deletion Request
Rights
You have the right
to request that we delete any of your personal information that we collected
from you and retained, subject to certain exceptions.
Exercising
Access, Data Portability, and Deletion Rights
To
exercise the access, data portability, and deletion rights described above,
please submit a verifiable consumer request to us by either:
·       Calling us at (888)
560-4671
·       Email: privacy@markel.com
·       Write to Markel
Corporation Privacy Office, 4521 Highwoods Parkway, Glen Allen, VA  23060
Only
you, or someone legally authorized to act on your behalf, may make a verifiable
consumer request related to your personal information. You may also make a
verifiable consumer request on behalf of your minor child.
You
may only make a verifiable consumer request for access or data portability
twice within a 12-month period. The verifiable consumer request must:
·       provide sufficient
information that allows us to reasonably verify you are the person about whom
we collected personal information or an authorized representative
·       describe your
request with sufficient detail that allows us to properly understand, evaluate,
and respond to it
We
will only use personal information provided in a verifiable consumer request to
verify the requestor’s identity or authority to make the request.
Personal
Information Sales Opt-Out and Opt-In Rights
We do
not and will not sell your personal information.  Also, we do not sell the
personal information of consumers we actually know are less than 16 years of
age, unless we receive affirmative authorization (the “right to opt-in”) from
either the consumer who is between 13 and 16 years of age, or the parent or
guardian of a consumer less than 13 years of age. Consumers who opt-in to
personal information sales may opt-out of future sales at any time.
Non-Discrimination
We
will not discriminate against you for exercising any of your CCPA rights, unless
permitted by the CCPA.
Other
California Privacy Rights
California’s
“Shine the Light” law (Civil Code Section § 1798.83) permits users of our website
that are California residents to request certain information regarding our
disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing
purposes. To make such a request, please send an email or write to the address
listed below.
Contact
Information
If
you have any questions or comments about this notice, the ways in which we
collect and use your information described in this Privacy Policy, your choices
and rights regarding such use, or wish to exercise your rights under California
law, please do not hesitate to contact us at:
·       Phone: (888)
560-4671
·       Website: www.markel.com/privacy-policy
·       Email: privacy@markel.com
·       Postal Address:
Markel Corporation Privacy Office, 4521 Highwoods Parkway, Glen Allen, VA
23060.
